SCOTT LOZANO

Full Stack Developer

SUMMARY

Experienced Software Engineer with multiple years of expertise building web applications. Skilled in Full Stack development, specializing in communications, Web3, security, and legal practices for cryptocurrency users. Skilled in JavaScript, JS frameworks, REST and Ruby on Rails. Strong communicator, leader and collaborator.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Security Engineer

01/2023 - Present

Exodus Movement Inc.

Fully Remote

- Led the engineering, containerization, and deployment of a Ruby on Rails, JavaScript, and PostgreSQL app to EKS in AWS, resulting in a 50% decrease in threats to Exodus users and a 20% acceleration in resolution time through enhanced API integrations.
- Cut reporting time of threats by 80% by creating an Electron desktop app for the brand protection team.
- Engineered and deployed repository of NodeJS scripts to automate reporting and threat removal, reducing the workload of security analysts by 90% and improving the organization's overall security posture.
- Improved the performance of a SEIM platform by 10% by developing a JavaScript Chrome extension that efficiently manipulates the DOM and text.

Freelance Software Developer

10/2021 - Present

Scott Tech

Fully Remote

- Build and launch a secure NFT solution for a graphic artist on Polygon and Solana, including the development and deployment of all necessary smart contracts using
- JavaScript and Solidity and metadata.
 Successfully deployed a secure NFT website on Polygon using Vue.js and IPFS, ensuring compliance with Open Zeppelin and ERC721 standards.
- Developed and launched a Ruby on Rails and JavaScript e-commerce site for an artist, increasing their profit margin by 20%.

Technical Support Engineer

06/2021 - 01/2023

Exodus Movement Inc.

Fully Remote

- Built a ReactJS Chrome extension that aggregates block explorers and verifies malicious crypto wallet addresses against a database, reducing response time to under 10 minutes on average, a key performance indicator for a team of over 100 people.
- Automated QA testing of a browser extension using Puppeteer, reducing manual regression script testing by 20%.
- Designed, developed & containerized a community-driven Discord bot on Kubernetes, boosting user engagement by 20%.

Portfolio Manager

06/2016 - 06/2021

Plymouth Housing

Seattle, WA

- Leading company-wide workshops on De-escalation, property management and training all new staff to decrease incidents by 10% year over year.
- Working closely with legal team to develop best practices and minimize risk by 10% annually.

EDUCATION

Web Development

04/2023 - 06/2023

Le Wagon

Online Cohort

• Web3JS, SCSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript ES6, Git, Heroku, Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL, Redis

Blockchain Developer, EVM Chains

2022 - 2022

Consensys Academy

Online Cohort

• Solidity, JavaScript, EthersJS, ReactJS, Truffle, Ganache, HardHat, Ethereum

Bachelor of Arts, Communications

2009 - 2012

University of Washington, Seattle

Seattle, WA

• Undergraduate studies in journalism, economics, international studies and Russian.



ACHIEVEMENTS

Enabled KPI achievement of consistently over 60% in CS dept.

Coded and maintain the chosen Hackathon project that is utilized by a 100+ person department

Created & Dockerized Security Program on AWS

Led development of a full-stack JS & Ruby App resulting in a 50% reduction of threat vectors affecting Exodus users in 6 months.

SKILLS

JavaScript · Ruby · Ruby on Rails ·

Node.js · RESTful APIs · PostgreSQL ·

HTML5 · CSS · HTML · Polygon ·

Blockchain · Hard-Hat · Smart Contracts ·

ReactJS · Puppeteer · VueJS · NextJS ·

Redis · Discord JS · Hardhat ·

Truffle Suite · Web3JS · Solana · Asana ·

Grafana · Sumo logic · Linux · TestRail ·

Git · Ethers JS · IPFS · Ethereum ·

Heroku · Amazon EKS · Docker ·

Kubernetes

LANGUAGES

English	Native	11111
Portugues	Advanced	Ш
JavaScript	Native	11111
Ruby on Rails	Native	11111

FIND ME ONLINE

in LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/angel-lozans

Portfolio

https://angellozan.github.io/myportfolio/

▼ Twitter

https://twitter.com/bytebuildcrypto

GitHub

https://github.com/AngelLozan